export const BUSINESSMANAGEMENTA2023 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The channel of distribution for the sale of tractors is",
A: "manufacturer agent > consumer.",
B: "manufacturer ———————rwholesaler ———> retailer.",
C: "wholesaler ————————>  retailee-consumer.",
D: "wholesaler -———————> agent ——————> consumer.",
answer: "B. Manufacturer → Wholesaler → Retailer",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A stock exchange speculator who buys shares in anticipation that prices are about to rise isa",
A: "bear.",
B: "bull.",
C: "broker.",
D: "stag.",
answer: "B. Bull",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The process of choosing among alternatives is referred to as",
A: "controlling.",
B: "decision-making.",
C: "planning.",
D: "problem solving.",
answer: "B. Decision-making",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following methods is used to correct adverse balance of payment?",
A: "Increase export",
B: "Increase taxes",
C: "Reduce consumption",
D: "Reduce export",
answer: "A. Increase export",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Debentures is a source of capital to a",
A: "co-operative society.",
B: "partnership.",
C: "public limited company.",
D: "sole proprietorship.",
answer: "C. Public limited company",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. One of the factors that contributes to inflation is",
A: "decrease in import.",
B: "decrease in aggregate demand.",
C: "increase in export.",
D: "increase in aggregate demand.",
answer: "D. Increase in aggregate demand",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. In Maslow’s Hierarchy of needs, the level where individual has a sense of belongingness andaffection is",
A: "esteem.",
B: "physiological.",
C: "security,",
D: "social.",
answer: "D. Social",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. An insurance policy which covers an event that is sure to occur in future is",
A: "fidelity.",
B: "fire.",
C: "life.",
D: "marine.",
answer: "C. Life",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The stage of the product life cycle at which XYZ Limited experiences low sales volume and replaces its existing products is",
A: "decline.",
B: "growth.",
C: "introduction.",
D: "maturity.",
answer: "C. Introduction",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Fishing, farming and mining are forms of",
A: "construction production.",
B: "extractive production.",
C: "service production.",
D: "tertiary production.",
answer: "B. Extractive production",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The individuals responsible for directing the affairs of organizations are",
A: "employers.",
B: "employees.",
C: "managers.",
D: "unions.",
answer: "C. Managers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A bank which is set up to provide credit facilities to improve certain sectors of the economy is referred to as",
A: "central bank.",
B: "commercial bank.",
C: "development bank.",
D: "merchant bank.",
answer: "C. Development bank",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following stages in the product life cycle indicates that sales of a product is at its peak?",
A: "Decline",
B: "Growth",
C: "Introduction",
D: "Maturity",
answer: "D. Maturity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A tax that takes a higher percentage of earnings from lower-income earners than those with higher-income is a",
A: "direct tax.",
B: "progressive tax.",
C: "proportional tax.",
D: "regressive tax",
answer: "D. Regressive tax",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. One condition for the success of small businesses 1s |",
A: "employ large number of staff.",
B: "control its cash flow.",
C: "redirect funds into private ventures.",
D: "open many retail outlets.",
answer: "B. Control its cash flow",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The retaining of power and authority in the hands of top management Is",
A: "centralization.",
B: "concentration.",
C: "decentralization.",
D: "devolution.",
answer: "A. Centralization",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The reason for international trade is the",
A: "balance of payment problems.",
B: "increase in the number of working population.",
C: "inability to produce all commodities in a country.",
D: "poor performance of the economy.",
answer: "C. Inability to produce all commodities in a country",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A short-term source of finance to an entrepreneur is",
A: "debentures.",
B: ". retained earnings.",
C: "shares.",
D: "trade credit.",
answer: "D. Trade credit",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following conditions distinguishes the public limited company from the private limited company?",
A: "Floating of shares to the general public.",
B: "Members enjoy limited liability.",
C: "Perpetual existence of the business.",
D: "It is a separate legal entity.",
answer: "A. Floating of shares to the general public",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Figure 1 depicts",
A: "circular chart",
B: "concentric chart.",
C: "horizontal chart.",
D: "vertical chart.",
answer: "A. Circular chart",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. In figure 1, the relationship between the Legal Advisor and the Managing Director is",
A: "functional.",
B: "line.",
C: "line and staff.",
D: "staff.",
answer: "A. Functional",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Identify the manager who should occupy the position marked ‘X’",
A: "general manager.",
B: "ICT manager.",
C: "marketing manager.",
D: "operations manager.",
answer: "B. ICT manager",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The Foreman, Accounts Clerk, Sales Person and Training Officer are",
A: "line staff.",
B: "middle level managers.",
C: "operational staff.",
D: "top management.",
answer: "C. Operational staff",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following positions in figure 1 makes strategic decisions?",
A: "Legal Advisor.",
B: "Managing Director.",
C: "Production Manager.",
D: "Training Officer.",
answer: "B. Managing Director",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Mr Amara was involved in an accident caused by Mr Fofanah. The insurance company paid Mr Amara the sum of Le 80, 000.00 as damages and sued Mr Fofanah to recover the amount. The principle of insurance involved is",
A: "contribution.",
B: "indemnity.",
C: "premium.",
D: "subrogation.",
answer: "D. Subrogation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The measuring of performance against set standards and determining causes of deviations and putting in corrective measures is",
A: "controlling.",
B: "leading.",
C: "planning.",
D: "organizing.",
answer: "A. Controlling",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Product differentiation is efficiently done by",
A: "advertising.",
B: "branding.",
C: "packaging.",
D: "pricing.",
answer: "B. Branding",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The business document which confers legal existence on a company is",
A: "articles of association.",
B: "certificate of incorporation.",
C: "memorandum of association.",
D: "prospectus.",
answer: "B. Certificate of incorporation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Consumer co-operative societies are financed by",
A: "creditors.",
B: "debtors.",
C: "government.",
D: "menibers.",
answer: "D. Members",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. One of the functions of the wholesaler is the",
A: "bearing of risks",
B: "developing of product",
C: "opening of retail outlets",
D: "provision of warehouse",
answer: "A. Bearing of risks",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The managerial role which relates to the ability to select, motivate and work with employeescomes under",
A: "figurehead role.",
B: "leader role.",
C: "liaison role.",
D: "monitor role.",
answer: "B. Leader role",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. A cheque has",
A: "two parties.",
B: "three parties.",
C: "four parties.",
D: "five parties.",
answer: "B. Three parties",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The estimates of revenue and expenditure of government for a fiscal year is referred to as",
A: "balance of payment.",
B: "budget statement.",
C: "statement of expenditure.",
D: "terms of trade.",
answer: "B. Budget statement",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The principle which states that authority should flow from top to bottom within an organization is",
A: "chain of command.",
B: "span of control.",
C: "unity of command.",
D: "unity of objective.",
answer: "A. Chain of command",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. An organizational structure with limited number of managers and supervisors is a",
A: "flat organizational structure.",
B: "functional structure.",
C: "line and staff structure.",
D: "tall organizational structure.",
answer: "A. Flat organizational structure",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The second step in the production, planning and control process is",
A: "dispatching.",
B: "loading.",
C: "routing.",
D: "scheduling.",
answer: "C. Routing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A set of characteristics that describes programmed decisions is",
A: "non-routine, uncertain and repetitive.",
B: "non-routine, procedural and automated.",
C: "repetitive, automated and uncertain.",
D: "repetitive, routine and automated.",
answer: "D. Repetitive, routine and automated",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. One of the steps in recruitment process is",
A: "jobanalysis.",
B: "performance appraisal.",
C: "physical examination.",
D: "training.",
answer: "A. Job analysis",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The financial institution with the mandate to supervise the banking system of a country is the",
A: "central bank.",
B: "commercial bank.",
C: "development bank. °",
D: "merchant bank.",
answer: "A. Central bank",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The type of training which involves the attachment of a newly employed staff to understudy an experienced staff is",
A: "classroom training.",
B: "correspondence training.",
C: "on-the-job training.",
D: "vestibule training.",
answer: "C. On-the-job training",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A speculator in a stock exchange market who sells shares in anticipation that prices are about to fall is a",
A: "bear.",
B: "broker.",
C: "bull.",
D: "stag.",
answer: "A. Bear",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The insurance principle that restores an insured to his former position is a",
A: "indemnity.",
B: "insurable interest.",
C: "proximate cause.",
D: "subrogation.",
answer: "A. Indemnity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. An advantage of globalization is that, it leads to the",
A: "creation of employment in a country.",
B: "imposition of restrictions on investment. , .",
C: "increase in the prices of goods and services.",
D: "introduction of trade barriers.",
answer: "A. Creation of employment in a country",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The relationship between the total volume of a country’s export and total imports is its",
A: "balance of trade.",
B: "balance of payment.",
C: "international trade.",
D: "terms of trade.",
answer: "A. Balance of trade",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. An example of restriction in international trade is the",
A: "imposition of import and export quota.",
B: "reduction of trade profit.",
C: "use of consular invoice.",
D: "use of proforma invoice.",
answer: "A. Imposition of import and export quota",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Ayo’s proposal constitutes",
A: "a counter offer.",
B: "a cross offer.",
C: "a promise.",
D: "an offer.",
answer: "A. A counter offer",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Mbemba’s action implies that, there was no",
A: "agreement.",
B: "capacity.",
C: "legality.",
D: "offer.",
answer: "A. Agreement",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. An agreement is said to be made when",
A: "an offeree gives consideration.",
B: "an offeree intends to give consideration.",
C: "the parties have contractual capacity.",
D: "there is a consensus.",
answer: "D. There is a consensus",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Specialization will result to",
A: "high product demand.",
B: "low production level.",
C: "increase in cost.",
D: "standardisation of products.",
answer: "D. Standardization of products",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. A stock exchange is a",
A: "capital market.",
B: "foreign exchange market.",
C: "money market.",
D: "parallel market.",
answer: "A. Capital market",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]